const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Developmentally, the cerebellum develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Diencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Metencephalon","bool":true},{"option":"Telencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalon","bool":false},{"option":"Myelencephalon","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The second pharyngeal pouch gives rise to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adenoids","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"Tubal tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Pharyngeal tonsil","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual tonsil","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"An 18-year-old boy has a head injury in which an immobile joint between the flat bones of the skull is disrupted. Which of the following types of joint is involved?","answers":[{"option":"Symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Condyloid joint","bool":false},{"option":"Suture","bool":true},{"option":"Hinge joint","bool":false},{"option":"Plane joint","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A 20-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of swelling below and behind the angle of the mandible. On examination, the doctor notices that it is a palpable jugulodigastric lymph node. Which of the following is the site of pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Tongue","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"Cheek","bool":false},{"option":"Upper eyelid","bool":false},{"option":"Lower eyelid","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A 25-year-old woman is brought to the outpatient department with a complaint of infection (ulcer) on the tongue. Which group of lymph nodes will become enlarged?","answers":[{"option":"Jugulo-omohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial cervical","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Jugulodigastric","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A 63-year-old man fails to maintain balance during linear motion. Which of the following sensory organs is responsible for detecting linear acceleration?","answers":[{"option":"Organ of corti","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear duct","bool":false},{"option":"Cristae","bool":false},{"option":"Saccules","bool":false},{"option":"Maculae","bool":true}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"An 8-year-old boy is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of nasal blockage and impairment of hearing. On examination, a diagnosis of adenoiditis is made due to inflammation of the tonsils. Where is the appropriate group of tonsils present?","answers":[{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Oropharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsillar fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Salpingopharynx","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A clinician examines the extrinsic musculature of the eyes of a 50-year-old female patient. All extraocular muscles are functioning fine except one. Which of the following muscles is affected based on the action mentioned?","answers":[{"option":"Superior oblique-looks medially and upwards","bool":true},{"option":"Medial rectus- looks medially","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectus-looks medially and upwards","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectus-looks downwards","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral rectus-looks laterally","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is a feature of complete anterior cleft anomaly?","answers":[{"option":"Cleft extends through maxilla and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lip, maxilla, soft palate, and hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through lips and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa on both sides","bool":false},{"option":"Cleft extends through upper lip and alveolar part of maxilla to the incisive fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A patient comes to the outpatient department with a complaint of pain in the throat and impairment of hearing. Otoscopic examination reveals the blockage of the auditory tube due to the spread of infection from the pharynx. What is the appropriate site of infection in the pharynx?","answers":[{"option":"Oropharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nasopharynx","bool":true},{"option":"Salpingopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngopharynx","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A patient's magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) reveals that the brain tumor is pressing on the superior orbital fissure. Which of the following structures will not be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Occulomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Nasociliary nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"While examining the lateral view of the X-ray of the skull, a radiologist points out a region that is the meeting point of the parietomastoid, occipitomastoid, and lambdoid sutures. What point is he referring to?","answers":[{"option":"Lambda","bool":false},{"option":"Inion","bool":false},{"option":"Bregma","bool":false},{"option":"Asterion","bool":true},{"option":"Pterion","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A surgeon, while performing surgery for removal of lymph nodes from the posterior triangle of the neck, is liable to damage which one of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the features of the pigmented epithelium layer of the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It consists of simple columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"The cells show phagocytic activity","bool":false},{"option":"It consists of stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It strongly adheres to Bruch's membrane of choroid","bool":false},{"option":"It contains stores of vitamin A","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following statement is incorrect about the retina of the eye?","answers":[{"option":"It is richly vascularized","bool":false},{"option":"It terminates anteriorly at orra serrata","bool":false},{"option":"It is the innermost layer of eye and is responsible for photoreception","bool":false},{"option":"It is easily detached from underlying choroid","bool":true},{"option":"A shallow depression called fovea is present in its posterior wall containing only cones","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The activation of the receptor by odorant particle further activates which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Ion channel","bool":false},{"option":"Beta subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false},{"option":"G-protein complex","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of a typical cervical vertebra?","answers":[{"option":"Triangular vertebral foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Bifid spinous process","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Dens","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Aqueous humor is secreted by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Ciliary body","bool":true},{"option":"Iris","bool":false},{"option":"Scleral glands","bool":false},{"option":"Arteries of retina","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Auditory signals are transmitted mainly by which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Outer hair cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular lamina","bool":false},{"option":"Inner hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Rods of Corti","bool":false},{"option":"Inner and central cells","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Bending of cilia of hair cells in the organ of Corti causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium conductance","bool":true},{"option":"Chloride conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium and sodium conductance","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which bone has a major contribution to the formation of the nasal septum?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal spine of frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary palatine crest","bool":false},{"option":"Rostrum of sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of ethmoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Perpendicular plate of palatine bone","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Bone of middle ear that covers the oval window develops from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sixth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following bones is not involved in the formation of pterion?","answers":[{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":true},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Parietal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding parts of bones of the head and neck?","answers":[{"option":"Styloid process is a part of temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal bone has a petrous part","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior nasal spine is a part of maxilla","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygoid process is a part of temporal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior nasal concha is a part of ethmoid bone","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What is the most common location for a thyroglossal duct cyst?","answers":[{"option":"Superior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior to hyoid bone","bool":true},{"option":"Superior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior to hyoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"At the base of tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Considering the structure of the eyeball, which of the following is not crossed by light rays?","answers":[{"option":"Vitreous humor","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true},{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A lesion of the optic chiasma causes which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of vision in the left eye","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous contralateral hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of vision in the right eye","bool":false},{"option":"Heteronymous bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The dorsal component of the auditory vesicle does not give rise to which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous labyrinth","bool":false},{"option":"Saccule","bool":true},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false},{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Due to the interruption of an optic tract, the field of vision on one side of each eye is affected. What is this condition called?","answers":[{"option":"Heteronymous hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Bitemporal hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral hemianopsia","bool":false},{"option":"Homonymous hemianopsia","bool":true},{"option":"Binasal hemianopsia","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"During a discussion, a teacher says that the given fossa has communication with the middle cranial fossa, orbital cavity, oral cavity, nasal cavity, and the foramen lacerum. Which of the following fossa is being discussed?","answers":[{"option":"Infratemporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal fossa","bool":false},{"option":"Pterygopalatine fossa","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following occurs during the pharyngeal stage of swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Vocal cords approximated and larynx is pulled upwards","bool":true},{"option":"Respiration is stimulated","bool":false},{"option":"Larynx is pulled downwards","bool":false},{"option":"Vocal cords open","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottis moves upwards","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Extraocular muscles are supplied by nerves that pass through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Optic canal","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen spinosum","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which facial nerve branches are present in the middle ear?","answers":[{"option":"Chorda tympani and greater petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Chorda tympani and nerve to stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Deep petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vidian nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater petrosal nerve and nerve to stapedius","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following arteries is not a branch of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior thyroid artery","bool":true},{"option":"Sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which structure does not take part in the formation of an external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cartilages","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior conchae","bool":true},{"option":"All of these take part","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal bone","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which nerve supplies the general sensation for the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglossal","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":true},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal","bool":false},{"option":"Facial","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The speech and tone are produced with the assistance of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Larynx","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue","bool":true},{"option":"Pharynx","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Posterior 1/3rd of the tongue is supplied by which nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Olfactory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following ions moves from endolymph to stereocilia to depolarize the hair cells?","answers":[{"option":"Mg2+","bool":false},{"option":"Cl-","bool":false},{"option":"Ca2+","bool":false},{"option":"K+","bool":true},{"option":"Na+","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a terminal branch of the seventh cranial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Buccal","bool":false},{"option":"Marginal mandibular","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Ophthalmic","bool":true},{"option":"Zygomatic","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the structure of taste buds?","answers":[{"option":"They are mainly located on the soft palate but few on the ventral surface of tongue","bool":false},{"option":"A taste bud consists of 10-12 cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sustentacular cells of taste buds are also known as gustatory cells","bool":false},{"option":"Apex of the taste buds communicate with the oral cavity through taste pore","bool":true},{"option":"Taste buds are embedded within epithelium covering the  filiform papillae","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Hearing loss associated with aging is termed as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true},{"option":"Conductive deafness","bool":false},{"option":"Sensorineural hearing loss","bool":false},{"option":"Ménière's disease","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"If the head is rotated to indicate a 'no' response, the movement occurs at which of the following joint?","answers":[{"option":"Atlantooccipital joint","bool":false},{"option":"C2-C3 joint","bool":false},{"option":"C3-C4 joint","bool":false},{"option":"Atlantoaxial joint","bool":true},{"option":"C7-T1 joint","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"In the case of vitamin A deficiency, keratomalacia occurs. Which of the following characterizes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Localized thickening of conjunctiva","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of conjunctiva and cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Unable to see in light or dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Patient cannot see in low light or in near dark condition","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness and clouding of cornea","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A colorblind person, who is a protanope, lacks which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Green cones","bool":false},{"option":"Blue cones","bool":false},{"option":"Red cones","bool":true},{"option":"White cones","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"In the process of light adaptation which of the following events occurs?","answers":[{"option":"The level of rhodopsin is high","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells transmit signals at the maximum rate","bool":false},{"option":"Photochemicals in photoreceptors are reduced to retinal and opsin","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin A is converted into retinal","bool":false},{"option":"The size of pupil is increased","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The intermediate column of the spinal cord gives rise to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Marginal layer","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior grey horn","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior grey horn","bool":false},{"option":"Mantle layer","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral grey horn","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Investing layer of the deep fascia of the neck encloses which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Digastric","bool":false},{"option":"Genohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The major site of a nose bleed is the anterior region of the medial wall of the nasal cavity. Which of the following arteries does not participate in the anastomosis at that site?","answers":[{"option":"Branches from sphenopalatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of lesser palatine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Branches of anterior ethmoidal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches of greater palatine artery","bool":false},{"option":"Branches from superior labial artery","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The middle ear cavity is present in which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Mastoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal bone","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of sphenoid","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The middle meningeal artery passes through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen lacerum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior orbital fissure","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen  spinosum","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Most of the refraction of light occurs in the eyes at which site?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior surface of cornea","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of lens","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior surface of sclera","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior surface of cornea","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Cricothyroid, a muscle of the larynx develops from which of the following pharyngeal arches?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":false},{"option":"Sixth pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Fourth pharyngeal arch","bool":true},{"option":"Fifth pharyngeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Sensory innervation of laryngopharynx is by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"External laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Internal branch of superior laryngeal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Pharyngeal branch of maxillary nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following muscles of the middle ear is supplied by the facial nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Superior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior auricular","bool":false},{"option":"Stapedius","bool":true},{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Serous cell are predominant cells of submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated ducts are wider and longer in the parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"All minor salivary gland are not encapsulated","bool":false},{"option":"All minor salivary glands are serous in nature","bool":true},{"option":"Demilune cells secrete lysozyme in sublingual gland","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The auditory ossicle(s) attached to the oval window is/are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"4th pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Hyoid arch","bool":true},{"option":"1st pharyngeal arch","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Where are the infrahyoid muscles present?","answers":[{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Submandibular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Sensory retina develops from which part of the optic cup?","answers":[{"option":"Pars optica retinae","bool":true},{"option":"Pars caeca retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Pars iridica retinae","bool":false},{"option":"Outer layer of the optic cup","bool":false},{"option":"Pars ciliaris retinae","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following cells mainly causes lateral inhibition?","answers":[{"option":"Ganglionic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Rods","bool":false},{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What substance combines with scotopsin to form rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"11-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"11-cis retinal","bool":true},{"option":"All-trans retinol","bool":false},{"option":"13-cis retinol","bool":false},{"option":"All-trans retinal","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Nightmares occur mostly during which sleep?","answers":[{"option":"REM sleep","bool":true},{"option":"NREM -2  sleep","bool":false},{"option":"Stage of drowsiness","bool":false},{"option":"NREM -3 sleep","bool":false},{"option":"NREM -1 sleep","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"An oblique facial cleft is a developmental anomaly that occurs due to failure of fusion of which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Two medial nasal prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Two maxillary prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence with each other","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with medial nasal prominence","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The olfactory epithelium is located at which site in the nasal cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior portion of the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"It is not present in the nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior and lateral portion of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior and lateral portion of nasal cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Superior portion of nasal cavity","bool":true}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Piriform aperture is bounded by which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Nasal bones and maxilla","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal and nasal bones","bool":false},{"option":"Nasal and zygomatic bones","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal and nasal bones","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Pterygoid venous plexus is a network of veins that drains into which of the following vein?","answers":[{"option":"Maxillary vein","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein","bool":false},{"option":"Cavernous sinus","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The parafollicular cells (C-cells) of the thyroid are derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Second pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Third pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"First pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Ultimobranchial body","bool":true},{"option":"Second pharyngeal cleft","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the retromandibular vein?","answers":[{"option":"It is formed anterior to the ear by the union of the superficial temporal and maxillary veins","bool":true},{"option":"It joins with the common facial vein to form external jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"It drains the side of head and superficial aspects of temporal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"It ultimately drains into internal jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"It is formed posterior to the ear by the union of the superficial temporal and maxillary veins","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following regarding mucous membrane of the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior one third of tongue is irregular with lymphoid aggregations called lingual tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"It is firmly bound to underlying muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior two third of tongue is covered by small projections called papillae","bool":false},{"option":"It is loosely bound to underlying muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Ventral surface of tongue is covered by a smooth mucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is the correct change in the photochemical process occurring due to absorption of light by rhodopsin?","answers":[{"option":"All-trans retinol to all-trans retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Metarhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to metarhodopsin","bool":true},{"option":"Bathorhodopsin to rhodopsin","bool":false},{"option":"Lumirhodopsin to bathorhodopsin","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is the sensory unit of the organ of Corti?","answers":[{"option":"Perilymph","bool":false},{"option":"Spiral ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"Basal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Hair cells","bool":true},{"option":"Endolymph","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The swallowing center is located in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamus","bool":false},{"option":"Pons","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebellum","bool":false},{"option":"Midbrain","bool":false},{"option":"Medulla oblongata","bool":true}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Taste buds of vallate papillae are most sensitive to which taste?","answers":[{"option":"Umami","bool":false},{"option":"Sour","bool":false},{"option":"Sweet","bool":false},{"option":"Salty","bool":false},{"option":"Bitter","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which nucleus in the brainstem receives fibers carrying taste sensations?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsal nuclei","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus ambiguus","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of pneumotaxic centre","bool":false},{"option":"Vasomotor centre","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleus of tractus solitarius","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Tensor tympani is supplied by which of the following nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibulocochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which is true regarding the venous drainage of face?","answers":[{"option":"Facial vein communicates with inferior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein drains into external jugular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein has unidirectional valves","bool":false},{"option":"Facial vein communicates with cavernous sinus through angular vein","bool":false},{"option":"Deep facial vein drains into the pterygoid plexus","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The axons of ganglionic cells transmitting action potential synapse in the midbrain with which of the following structure?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior colliculus","bool":false},{"option":"Optic radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Superior colliculus","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following extrinsic muscles of the tongue is attached to the body of mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Hyoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Geniohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Styloglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Genioglossus","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The facial primordial appearance depends on the inductive influence of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Prosencephalic organizing centre","bool":true},{"option":"Neural tube","bool":false},{"option":"Notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Mesencephalic organizing centre","bool":false},{"option":"Stomodeum","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following nerve does not supply sensory innervation to the face?","answers":[{"option":"Deep temporal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Buccal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supratrochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticofacial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following statements is true regarding the scalp?","answers":[{"option":"Wounds do not bleed easily","bool":false},{"option":"Blood vessels and nerves lie in  loose areolar tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Infections can easily spread through emissary veins into the cranial cavity","bool":true},{"option":"Wounds gape when injury is superficial to aponeurosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bleeding beneath periosteum extends through whole length of scalp","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The infraorbital foramen is an opening in which of the following bones?","answers":[{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomatic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Greater wing of the sphenoid bone","bool":false},{"option":"Frontal bone","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary bone","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following ion is responsible for the depolarization of olfactory receptor cells after their binding with the odor molecule?","answers":[{"option":"K+ ion","bool":false},{"option":"Cl- ion","bool":false},{"option":"Na+ ion","bool":true},{"option":"H+ ion","bool":false},{"option":"Ca+2 ion","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The nasolacrimal duct opens into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Superior meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Hiatus semilunaris","bool":false},{"option":"Spheno-ethmoidal recess","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior meatus","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following muscles is not supplied by the mandibular nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Buccinator","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which neurotransmitter is released by rods and cones in their synapse with bipolar cells?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The primary palate forms which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Soft palate","bool":false},{"option":"Upper jaw","bool":false},{"option":"Hard palate anterior to the incisive fossa","bool":true},{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral palatine process","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The refractive power of the lens is expressed in which of the following units?","answers":[{"option":"Hertz","bool":false},{"option":"Diopters","bool":true},{"option":"Microns","bool":false},{"option":"Dynes","bool":false},{"option":"Decibels","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is the relation of the facial nerve with the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Deep to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to arteries","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to vein","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What is the relation of the retromandibular vein with the parotid gland?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial to the facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Deep to the gland","bool":true},{"option":"Superficial to gland","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial to facial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The six extraocular muscles are supplied by which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Olfactory and oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducent nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Trochlear and facial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor, trochlear, and abducent nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trigeminal and facial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The triangular primary palate is formed by the fusion of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Medial nasal prominence","bool":true},{"option":"Maxillary prominence with lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two lateral nasal prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two maxillary prominence","bool":false},{"option":"Two mandibular prominence","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following structures does not originate from the utricular portion of the otic vesicle?","answers":[{"option":"Endolymphatic duct","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlear duct","bool":true},{"option":"Endolymphatic sac","bool":false},{"option":"Utricle","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Visual fibers also pass through the pretectal nucleus in the midbrain. Pretectal nucleus is associated with which of the following function?","answers":[{"option":"Pupillary light reflex","bool":true},{"option":"Attenuation reflex","bool":false},{"option":"Balance and equilibrium","bool":false},{"option":"Color sensation","bool":false},{"option":"Accommodation reflex","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Visual pathway does not include which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":true},{"option":"Cortical area 17","bool":false},{"option":"Optic tract","bool":false},{"option":"Optic chiasma","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following nerves supplies the muscles of facial expression?","answers":[{"option":"Glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Facial nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Mandibular division of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Vagus nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which muscle takes part in the formation of palatine aponeurosis?","answers":[{"option":"Tensor tympani","bool":false},{"option":"Palatoglossus","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Tensor veli palatini","bool":true},{"option":"Musculus uvulae","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which one of the following structures is not a content of the posterior triangle of the neck?","answers":[{"option":"Trunks of brachial plexus","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral plexus","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Accessory nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is not a branch of the maxillary division of the trigeminal nerve?","answers":[{"option":"Zygomaticofacial nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraorbital nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior superior alveolar nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Zygomaticotemporal nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which primary cortical sensory area is located in the middle of the superior temporal gyrus?","answers":[{"option":"Hearing","bool":true},{"option":"Smell","bool":false},{"option":"Vision","bool":false},{"option":"Touch","bool":false},{"option":"Taste","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The infratemporal fossa communicates with the middle cranial fossa through which of the following foramen?","answers":[{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":true},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Greater palatine foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Stylomastoid foramen","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser palatine foramen","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"If the lingual nerve is damaged which of the following condition is likely to occur?","answers":[{"option":"Upper gingival sensations are lost","bool":false},{"option":"Taste sensation on posterior one third of tongue is lost","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue is deviated to the left","bool":false},{"option":"Flattening of palatoglossal arch occurs","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular secretions are lost","bool":true}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the lacrimal apparatus?","answers":[{"option":"Tears flow to the lacrimal puncta","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands drain into superficial parotid lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Tears collect in the conjunctival fornix","bool":false},{"option":"Secretions produced are called tears","bool":false},{"option":"Lacrimal glands are of simple tubuloacinar type","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A person injures his mandible (ramus) in an accident. Which boundary of the wall of the infratemporal fossa does it form?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Medial wall","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral wall","bool":true}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which is not true about the retina?","answers":[{"option":"It terminates at ora serrata","bool":false},{"option":"It is highly vascular","bool":false},{"option":"It is the photoreceptor layer","bool":false},{"option":"Two retinal layers can easily be detached","bool":false},{"option":"The innermost layer of the retina contains the rods and cones","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following nerves provide sensory supply to the skin overlying the angle of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Mandibular branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater occipital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillary branch of trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Greater auricular nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A person presents with his right eye looking \"down and out\" with double vision (diplopia) when looking at the right. He has a lesion in which of the following nerves?","answers":[{"option":"Left trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Right oculomotor nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Left trigeminal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Left oculomotor nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Vitamin A is stored in which of the following form?","answers":[{"option":"Retinyl esters","bool":true},{"option":"All trans retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol","bool":false},{"option":"11-cis retinal","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Passavant's ridge helps to close the nasopharyngeal isthmus during swallowing.Which muscle contracts to produce the passavant's ridge?","answers":[{"option":"Fibers of pharyngeal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Upper most fibers of palatopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Fibers of tensor palatini","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of levator palatini","bool":false},{"option":"Fibers of palatoglossus","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the connections of pterygopalatine ganglion?","answers":[{"option":"Parasympathetic root is derived from deep petrosal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Secretomotor fibers from the sympathetic root supply the lacrimal gland and paranasal sinuses","bool":false},{"option":"The sensory or parasympathetic root of ganglion is formed by branches of glossopharyngeal nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Sympathetic root is derived from nerve of pterygoid canal","bool":true},{"option":"Sensory root comes from facial nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is the only branch coming from the medial side of the external carotid artery?","answers":[{"option":"Facial artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending pharyngeal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Occipital artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior thyroid artery","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual artery","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"According to the psychoanalytic theory, what is the phenomenon that occurs if an issue or conflict in a psychosexual stage remains unresolved?","answers":[{"option":"Expressiveness","bool":false},{"option":"Fixation","bool":true},{"option":"Neuroticism","bool":false},{"option":"Regression","bool":false},{"option":"Retentiveness","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following muscles contributes to the formation of the floor of the submandibular triangle along with the hyoglossus muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Omohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Thyropharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Mylohyoid","bool":true},{"option":"Thyrohyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Sternohyoid","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which spinal nerve does not have an associated dermatome?","answers":[{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true},{"option":"T1","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A 34-year-old man visits the hospital with the complaint of being unable to shrug his shoulder after an injury. Which of the following is affected?","answers":[{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":true},{"option":"Condyloid canal","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglossal canal","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior cranial foramen","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The medial nasal prominences form which of the following in the external nose?","answers":[{"option":"Dorsum of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Apex of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Root of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Ala of the nose","bool":false},{"option":"Ethmoid bone","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"An infection of the eustachian tube causes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Acute mastoiditis","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis media","bool":true},{"option":"Otitis externa","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Activation of receptor by an odorant particle is by what mechanism?","answers":[{"option":"PI3 kinase","bool":false},{"option":"G protein complex","bool":true},{"option":"Ion channel","bool":false},{"option":"β subunit","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine complex","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A lesion of the oculomotor nerve result in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Esotropia","bool":false},{"option":"Pupillary contriction","bool":false},{"option":"Exotropia","bool":true},{"option":"Ciliary muscle spasm","bool":false},{"option":"Myopia","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following does not supply the subcutaneous structures?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C4","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C1","bool":true}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The submandibular lymph nodes are present in which triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric triangle","bool":true},{"option":"Submental triangle","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following equalizes the pressure between the external atmosphere and the middle ear cavity?","answers":[{"option":"External ear","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Pinna","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Auricle","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What happens to the vocal cords while swallowing?","answers":[{"option":"Opened","bool":false},{"option":"Overlapped","bool":false},{"option":"Approximated","bool":true},{"option":"No change","bool":false},{"option":"Gapped by membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A teacher discussed a fossa inferior and deep to the zygomatic arch and posterior to the maxilla. The appropriate fossa being discussed is?","answers":[{"option":"Infratemporal","bool":true},{"option":"Pterygopalatine","bool":false},{"option":"Occipital","bool":false},{"option":"Temporal","bool":false},{"option":"Middle cranial","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The suspensory ligaments of the eye are an extension of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tenon's capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Periorbital fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Deep fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital septum","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following papillae are damaged if there is damage to the tongue anterior to the terminal sulcus?","answers":[{"option":"Foliate","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform","bool":false},{"option":"Circumvallate","bool":true},{"option":"Filiform","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"In which region are cristae found?","answers":[{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular duct","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic cavity","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The stereocilia of the hair cells of the organ of Corti are embedded in?","answers":[{"option":"Basilar membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Tympanic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Tectorial membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Otolithic membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Reissner membrane","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Prevertebral fascia forms the floor of which triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Muscular triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Omohyoid trianlge","bool":false},{"option":"Carotid triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Digastric triangle","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior triangle","bool":true}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A man received a strong blow to the anterior aspect of the mandible during a fight. The tympanic plate of the external auditory meatus was affected. The temporomandibular joint has undergone which type of dislocation?","answers":[{"option":"Medial","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Superior","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A student is studying about a muscle that forms the boundaries of both anterior and posterior triangles. Which of the following is the appropriate muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Sternocleidomastoid","bool":true},{"option":"Trapezius","bool":false},{"option":"Suprahyoid","bool":false},{"option":"Levator scapulae","bool":false},{"option":"Infrahyoid","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Through which of the following structures light doesn't pass?","answers":[{"option":"Lens","bool":false},{"option":"Vitreous body","bool":false},{"option":"Pupil","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Sclera","bool":true}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect about the structures of the tongue?","answers":[{"option":"It has a core of skeletal muscles","bool":false},{"option":"It has lymphoid aggregates called lymphoid tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"It is lined by stratified columnar epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"It has epithelial projections called papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous glands are present in the deep part of tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which nucleus of the thalamus is responsible for carrying fibers to the auditory cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Medial geniculate body","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsomedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral geniculate body","bool":false},{"option":"Ventroposteromedial nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Venteroposterolateral nucleus","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The pharyngeal plexus does not supply which of the following mucles?","answers":[{"option":"Stylopharyngeus","bool":true},{"option":"Middle constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior constrictor","bool":false},{"option":"Palatopharyngeus","bool":false},{"option":"Superior constrictor","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Striated ducts are not present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland","bool":false},{"option":"Submandibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Sublingual gland","bool":false},{"option":"Exocrine pancreas","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"In phototransduction, what happens in the presence of light?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in the number of open Na+ channels","bool":false},{"option":"Increased Ca+ conductance","bool":false},{"option":"Reduced cAMP and closed Na+ channel","bool":true},{"option":"Decreased phosphodiestearse activity","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased transducin activity","bool":false}]},{"id":137,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The sublingual gland produces which type of secretions?","answers":[{"option":"Predominantly serous","bool":false},{"option":"Seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Serous","bool":false},{"option":"Mucous","bool":false},{"option":"Predominantly mucous","bool":true}]},{"id":138,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What term describes the lens of the eye becoming less elastic with the passage of time?","answers":[{"option":"Anosmia","bool":false},{"option":"Aguesia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbyopia","bool":true},{"option":"Insomnia","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The deficiency of vitamin A causes a pathological condition called xerophthalmia. Which of the following correctly describes it?","answers":[{"option":"Poor vision in dim light","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of the cornea and conjuctiva","bool":true},{"option":"Thickening of a part of cornea","bool":false},{"option":"Poor vision at night","bool":false},{"option":"Dryness of cornea along with cloudy appearance","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following nerves are not present in the posterior triangle?","answers":[{"option":"Great auricular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal part of accessory nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse cervical nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Supraclavicular nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent laryngeal nerve","bool":true}]},{"id":141,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"If the anterior 2/3rd portion of the tongue is damaged then which of the following will be lost?","answers":[{"option":"Vallate papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Filiform papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Fungiform papillae","bool":true},{"option":"Lingual papillae","bool":false},{"option":"Foliate papillae","bool":false}]},{"id":142,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which epithelium lines the interlobular, interlobar, and excretory duct of the lingual gland respectively?","answers":[{"option":"Stratified columnar, simple cuboidal, pseudostratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"All three are stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, simple cuboidal, stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, stratified columnar, stratified columnar","bool":false},{"option":"Simple cuboidal, pseudostratified columnar, stratified columnar","bool":true}]},{"id":143,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"What is the hearing loss in old age termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Otitis media","bool":false},{"option":"Presbycusis","bool":true},{"option":"Vestibular neuronitis","bool":false},{"option":"Otitis sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Labyrinthitis","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which fibers are responsible for the retraction of the mandible?","answers":[{"option":"Middle fibers of temporalis","bool":false},{"option":"Masseter","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral pterygoid","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior fibers of temporalis","bool":true},{"option":"Medial pterygoid","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following muscles causes forceful closure of the eyes?","answers":[{"option":"Procerus","bool":false},{"option":"Palpebral part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"Orbital part of orbicularis oculi","bool":true},{"option":"Lacrimal part of orbicularis oculi","bool":false},{"option":"None of them","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A man is having problems maintaining balance while rotating his head. Which of the following has the defect?","answers":[{"option":"Cochlea","bool":false},{"option":"Semicircular canals","bool":true},{"option":"Cilia","bool":false},{"option":"Eustachian tube","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following forms are most easily interconvertible?","answers":[{"option":"Retinoic acid and beta-carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and retinoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Retinol and retinyl esters","bool":false},{"option":"Retinal and retinol","bool":true}]},{"id":148,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following does not drain into the middle nasal meatus?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Maxillay sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior ethmoidal air cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sphenoidal sinus","bool":true}]},{"id":149,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which structure does not pass through the superior orbital fissure?","answers":[{"option":"Superior ophthalmic vein","bool":false},{"option":"Oculomotor nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Optic nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Trochlear nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Abducens nerve","bool":false}]},{"id":150,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A girl is facing pre-pubertal acne. The doctor warns her about not squeezing any pimples and prescribes her some special cream for the tip of the nose and the upper lip region acne. What is the most likely reason?","answers":[{"option":"This area has direct dural venous drainage","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"This area requires more special care than the others","bool":false},{"option":"This area is richly vascularized","bool":false},{"option":"This area is more prone to acne","bool":false}]},{"id":151,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following structures is a content of the pterygopalatine fossa?","answers":[{"option":"3rd part of the maxillary artery","bool":true},{"option":"Infraorbital nerve","bool":false},{"option":"Otic ganglion","bool":false},{"option":"1st part of the maxillary artery","bool":false},{"option":"2nd part of maxillary artery","bool":false}]},{"id":152,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following statements regarding the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Lateral swellings merge and overlap tuberculum impar to form the anterior 2/3rd of the tongue","bool":false},{"option":"The development of tongue begins in the fourth week of embryonic life","bool":false},{"option":"The tuberculum impar eventually degenerates","bool":false},{"option":"Hypobranchial eminemce is derived from the 3rd and 4th pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"Muscles of the tongue are derived from ectoderm","bool":true}]},{"id":153,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following is true regarding the salivary glands?","answers":[{"option":"Submandibular gland secretions are mainly mucus","bool":false},{"option":"The submandibular gland is the largest salivary gland","bool":false},{"option":"20% of salivary secretions are produced by small salivary glands","bool":false},{"option":"Parotid gland secretions are seromucous","bool":false},{"option":"Lingual gland secretions are predominantly mucus","bool":true}]},{"id":154,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"The contrast border in the visual image is enhanced due to the lateral inhibition of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar cells","bool":false},{"option":"Amacrine cells","bool":false},{"option":"Photoreceptors","bool":false},{"option":"Horizontal cells","bool":true},{"option":"Ganglionic cells","bool":false}]},{"id":155,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Umami taste fibers are related to?","answers":[{"option":"Alkaloids","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamate","bool":true},{"option":"Acetic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Organic substances containing nitrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false}]},{"id":156,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Hypermetropia is treated by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Concave lens","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Convex lens","bool":true},{"option":"Contact lens","bool":false},{"option":"Concavo convex lens","bool":false}]},{"id":157,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Myopia is corrected by what type of lens?","answers":[{"option":"Convex","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Concave","bool":true},{"option":"Imaginary","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed","bool":false}]},{"id":158,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"A 25-year-old man comes into the outpatient department with the complaint of not being able to lift his shoulder. What is the most probable site of the lesion that is causing this?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen ovale","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen magnum","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen rotundum","bool":false},{"option":"Jugular foramen","bool":true}]},{"id":159,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Which of the following statements about the tongue is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Anterior two-thirds of the tongue is innervated differently from the posterior one-third","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen cecum is the site of thyroid migration","bool":false},{"option":"Musculature of the tongue is derived from ectoderm","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior two-thirds of the tongue is formed by lateral lingual swellings","bool":false},{"option":"Taste buds develop on the dorsal surface of tongue","bool":false}]},{"id":160,"info":"2nd-year/head-and-neck/2020","question":"Ossification and bone formation does not occur in which of the following structures?","answers":[{"option":"Hard palate","bool":false},{"option":"Middle ear cavity","bool":false},{"option":"Soft palate","bool":true},{"option":"Nasal septum","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral leg compartment","bool":false}]}]
export default arr